The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
- Documents relating to Lancashire, Cheshire and other counties, 14th century-19th century; GB/418/E/7/1-E/7/6; GB/418/Main/1; 318 files; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Sedgley, co Staffs, 1668-1825; GB/418/E.7.1-E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/25; 50 files; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year [of land in Sedgley], 29 Dec 1822; GB/418/E.7.3 (140); GB/418/Main/1/25/46; Chetham's Library
      From Mrs Sarah Marsh to Dudley Fereday.
    - Conveyance and assignment of the life estate and interest of Samuel Fereday in certain real and personal property under the will of Dudley Bagley, 5 May 1824; GB/418/E.7.2 (98); GB/418/Main/1/25/47; Chetham's Library
      From Charles Henry Molineux, surviving assignee of the estate of Samuel Fereday, a bankrupt, to Dudley Fereday, Rev Proctor Robinson and Richard Smith.
    - Further charge upon freehold and copyhold messuages etc at Gornall for securing £200 and interest, 27 Jun 1824; GB/418/E.7.2 (89); GB/418/Main/1/25/48; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of parcel of land called the Wet Piece at Eve Lane in the parish of Sedgley, co Staffs for one year at a peppercorn rent, 19 May 1825; GB/418/E.7.2 (77); GB/418/Main/1/25/49; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Dudley and the Rev John Dudley to Dudley Fereday.
    - Release of a close of land called Wet Piece at Eve Lane in the parish of Sedgley, co Staffs, 20 May 1825; GB/418/E.7.2 (78); GB/418/Main/1/25/50; Chetham's Library
      From the heirs at law of John Keelinge to Dudley Fereday. With a covenant to levy a fine.
  - Documents relating to Stretford, co Lancs, 1766 & 1837; GB/418/E.7.2 (88) & E.7.4 (177); GB/418/Main/1/26; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of the tenement of James Moores, 15 Jan 1766; GB/418/E.7.4 (177); GB/418/Main/1/26/1; Chetham's Library
      From Rev James Benn of Blakeley (Blackley) and others to William Higinbotham.
    - Will and probate of Richard Pearson, 11 Dec 1837; GB/418/E.7.2 (88); GB/418/Main/1/26/2; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1705-1821; GB/418/E.7.3 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/27; 12 files; Chetham's Library
    - Exemplification of a recovery suffered by Mr Chetham of Turton for lands in Derbyshire, 1705; GB/418/E.7.3 (101); GB/418/Main/1/27/1; Chetham's Library
    - Deed to declare the uses of a Fine of some land in Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Jul 1742; GB/418/E.7.3 (159); GB/418/Main/1/27/2; Chetham's Library
      Between John Willows of Leicester and his wife and Edward Timson of Leicester and his wife, and Daniel Pycroft of Burton upon Trent and John Hudson of Sutton on the Hill.
    - Conveyance of some land at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys in trust for Samuel Bentley, 29 Sep 1767; GB/418/E.7.4 (161); GB/418/Main/1/27/3; Chetham's Library
      Between Isaac Hawkins of Burton upon Trent, Robert Lea of Linton, co Derbys, and Thomas Dickson of Burton, and Daniel Smith of Lichfield.
    - Mortgage on property and land in Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 14 Apr 1768; GB/418/E.7.3 (160); GB/418/Main/1/27/4; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Bentley to William Batkin.
    - Counterpart lease of premises in Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1801; GB/418/E.7.3 (153); GB/418/Main/1/27/5; Chetham's Library
      From the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester to Henry Hall.
      Annual rent: £180.
    - Agreement for letting a mill and a farm at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1801; GB/418/E.7.3 (154); GB/418/Main/1/27/6; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester and Henry Hall.
      Rent: £95.
    - Agreement for letting a farm at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (151); GB/418/Main/1/27/7; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital and Charles Osborne. Rent: £300.
    - Agreement for letting a farm at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (152); GB/418/Main/1/27/8; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester and William Eaton.
      Rent: £375.
    - Agreement for letting a farm at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (155); GB/418/Main/1/27/9; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester and Francis Pakeman.
      Rent: £95
    - Agreement for letting a farm at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (156); GB/418/Main/1/27/10; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester and Thomas Hall.
    - Agreement for letting a farm at Thurvaston, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (157); GB/418/Main/1/27/11; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital and John Bradshaw.
      Rent: £150.
    - Agreement for letting several closes of land at Sutton on the Hill, co Derbys, 1 Oct 1821; GB/418/E.7.3 (158); GB/418/Main/1/27/12; Chetham's Library
      Between the Governors of Chetham's Hospital, Manchester and William Legh Clowes.
      Rent: £52 10s 0d.
  - Documents relating to Swinton, co Lancs, 1816-1834; GB/418/E.7.1 & E.7.4; GB/418/Main/1/28; 6 files; Chetham's Library
    - Declaration of Trusts of £150 advanced on the security of tolls from Swinton Turnpike to Thomas and John Barlow, 7 Sep 1816; GB/418/E.7.4 (224); GB/418/Main/1/28/1; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls from Swinton Turnpikes to Thomas Fildes and James Smith White, 13 Mar 1823; GB/418/E.7.4 (216); GB/418/Main/1/28/2; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls of the Swinton district of Turnpike Roads to John Greaves for securing £2000 and interest, 6 Jan 1829; GB/418/E.7.1 (11); GB/418/Main/1/28/3; Chetham's Library
      Also assignment thereof to Mrs Margaret Hibbert.
    - Release from Elizabeth Chadwick to the Trustees under the will of the late Elias Chadwick Esq, 3 Oct 1829; GB/418/E.7.1 (30); GB/418/Main/1/28/4; Chetham's Library
    - Release from Elizabeth Chadwick to the Trustees under the will of the late Elias Chadwick Esq, 27 Dec 1831; GB/418/E.7.1 (29); GB/418/Main/1/28/5; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of the tolls arising from Swinton Turnpike to Charles Cooke Esq for securing £200 and interest, 28 Mar 1828 & 26 Dec 1834; GB/418/E.7.1 (20); GB/418/Main/1/28/6; Chetham's Library
      With attached assignment of £200 and interest owing on security of the tolls etc from Charles Cooke to Miss Susanna Dorothea Cooke.
  - Documents relating to Taxal, co Ches, 1655-1890; GB/418/E.7.5- E.7.6; GB/418/Main/1/29; 73 files; Chetham's Library
    - Grant and release of Castede Pasture and Goyte Pasture in Taxal co Ches, 2 Apr 1655; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-1); GB/418/Main/1/29/1; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Leigh to Gilbert Ireland.
    - Lease and release of Castede Pasture and Goyte Pasture, 28 Mar 1655; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-2); GB/418/Main/1/29/2; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Legh, Richard Legh to Francis Dickson.
    - Grant and release of Hearwood House etc in parish of Taxal co Ches, 22 Aug 1707; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-3); GB/418/Main/1/29/3; Chetham's Library
      Henry Slack, John Dickson, Richard Slack, Thomas Lomas, John Houghton and Hugh Whishaw.
    - Assignment of the renewal of a term of 500 years, 25 Mar 1710; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-4); GB/418/Main/1/29/4; Chetham's Library
      From Mary Slack, widow of Henry Slack to Nicholas Kidd.
    - Lease for 6 months of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 24 Mar 1711; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-5); GB/418/Main/1/29/5; Chetham's Library
      From John Dickson to John Bradshaw.
    - Conveyance of Intack in Taxal co Ches, 12 Nov 1718; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-6); GB/418/Main/1/29/6; Chetham's Library
      From Mary William, Ann and Thomas Redferne to John Shallcross.
    - Release in trust of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 25 Mar 1711; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-7); GB/418/Main/1/29/7; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of Hearwood [House] in Taxal co Ches, 15 Jul 1731; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-8); GB/418/Main/1/29/8; Chetham's Library
      From William and Hugh Kidd to William Slack.
    - Lease for a year and release of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 16 & 17 Jul 1731; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-9) & (2-10); GB/418/Main/1/29/9; Chetham's Library
      Lease from Sarah Grindon and John Dixon to Hugh Kidd. Release from Sarah Kidd, William Kidd and John Dixon to Hugh Kidd of Foxholes, parish of Alstone Field, co Staffs.
    - Release of lands in the parish of Taxal co Ches, 25 Jan 1745; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-11); GB/418/Main/1/29/10; Chetham's Library
      From Hugh Kidd to John Gilman.
    - Conveyance of messuage called Goy[t]shead in Taxal co Ches, 29 Jun 1762; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-12); GB/418/Main/1/29/11; Chetham's Library
      From John Dixon to his son James Dixon.
    - Settlement of land etc in Taxal called Castidge and the Stake, the Middlemoss and the Further Moss, 11 & 12 Feb 1750; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-13); GB/418/Main/1/29/12; Chetham's Library
      From John Dixon to his son John Dixon.
    - Release of Barkers Farm in Fernileigh, co Derbys, 14 Feb 1767; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-13); GB/418/Main/1/29/13; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Needham to Samuel Needham.
    - Mortgage for 500 years of Castidge estate in Taxal co Ches, nd [18th century]; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-14); GB/418/Main/1/29/14; Chetham's Library
      From John Dixon to Edward Dixon.
    - Lease and release of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 24 & 25 Mar 1774; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-15) & (2-16); GB/418/Main/1/29/15; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Hugh Kidd to William Kidd.
    - Deed to lead the uses of a fine, 1 Apr 1777; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-17); GB/418/Main/1/29/16; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Dixon and his wife Martha, and James Dixon and his wife Ellen to Henry Longden.
    - Final agreement concerning lands etc in Taxal co Ches, 3 Apr 1777; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-18); GB/418/Main/1/29/17; Chetham's Library
      Between Henry Longden, plaintiff and Edward Dixon, Martha his wife, James Dixon and Ellen his wife, defendants.
    - Assignment of a mortgage term previous to the conveyance of the inheritance to the assignor in trust to attend the same, 29 Jul 1777; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-19); GB/418/Main/1/29/18; Chetham's Library
      Castidge estate together with part of the Stake, the Middle Moss and the Further Moss. From Edward Dixon to John Dickinson.
    - Conveyance of the Castidge estate, 15 Aug 1777; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-20); GB/418/Main/1/29/19; Chetham's Library
      From John Dixon the elder and John Dixon the younger to Edward Dixon.
    - Deed of appointment: mortgage for £500 and interest at £1.10%, 1 Jan 1778; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-21); GB/418/Main/1/29/20; Chetham's Library
      From James Dixon to Isaac Wheeldon.
    - Release of messuages and lands at Fernileigh, co Derbys, 21 Mar 1780; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-22); GB/418/Main/1/29/21; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Longden to Samuel Needham.
    - Lease for possession of Fernileigh, co Derbys, 21 Mar 1780; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-23); GB/418/Main/1/29/22; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for possession of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 18 Dec 1781; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-24); GB/418/Main/1/29/23; Chetham's Library
      From William Kidd to John Birtles.
    - Mortgage in fee of Hearwood House in Taxall co Ches, 19 Dec 1781; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-25); GB/418/Main/1/29/24; Chetham's Library
      From William Kidd and his wife Ann to John Birtles.
    - Lease for a year of Hearwood House, Taxall co Ches, 1 Jan 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-26); GB/418/Main/1/29/25; Chetham's Library
      From Simon Debank and Elisabeth his wife to Thomas Lomas.
    - Mortgage in fee of Hearwood House, Taxall for securing £350 and interest, 2 Jan 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-27); GB/418/Main/1/29/26; Chetham's Library
      From Simon Debank to Thomas Lomas.
    - Bond for £700, 2 Jan 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-28); GB/418/Main/1/29/27; Chetham's Library
      William Kidd, Ann Kidd, Samuel Kidd and Hugh Kidd bound to Thomas Lomas.
    - Final agreement concerning Hearwood in Taxal co Ches, 4 Apr 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-29); GB/418/Main/1/29/28; Chetham's Library
      Between Thomas Lomas, plaintiff, and Simon Debank, Elisabeth his wife, William, Samuel and Hugh Kidd, defendants.
    - Lease for possession of Hearwood House, Taxal co Ches, 30 Sep 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-30); GB/418/Main/1/29/29; Chetham's Library
      From William Kidd to Moses Charlesworth.
    - Release of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 1 Oct 1793; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-31); GB/418/Main/1/29/30; Chetham's Library
      From William Kidd and others to Hugh Kidd and William Kidd.
    - Assignment of the remainder of a term of 99 years to Hearwood estate, Taxal co Ches, 22 Apr 1794; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-32); GB/418/Main/1/29/31; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Kidd to Hugh Kidd.
    - Lease and release by way of mortgage for securing £700 and interest of Hearwood Estate, Taxal co Ches, 2 & 3 Jun 1794; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-33) & (2-34); GB/418/Main/1/29/32; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Lomas, Hugh and William Kidd and Moses Charlesworth to Cornelius Flint.
    - Lease and release of a messuage etc called Goyt's Head in Taxal co Ches, 25 Dec 1795; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-35) & (2-36); GB/418/Main/1/29/33; Chetham's Library
      From James Dixon and his mortgagee to John Bower Jodrell and his trustee. Release with an assignment of the remainder of a term of 2000 years in trust to attend the inheritance
    - Deed of covenants charging mortgage premises of Hearwood estate with a further sum of £400 and interest, 10 Dec 1796; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-37); GB/418/Main/1/29/34; Chetham's Library
      From Hugh Kidd to Cornelius Flint.
    - Release of Hearwood estate, 29 Sep 1798; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-38); GB/418/Main/1/29/35; Chetham's Library
      From Cornelius Flint, Hugh Kidd and William Brittlebank to Matthew Pickford.
    - Lease for a year of a messuage called Castids in Taxal co Ches, 1 Feb 1799; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-39); GB/418/Main/1/29/36; Chetham's Library
      From John Dixon to Matthew Pickford.
    - Conveyance of the Castids estate with assignment of the residue of a term of 500 years, 2 Feb 1799; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-40); GB/418/Main/1/29/37; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of the Castids estate, 5 Dec 1797; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-42); GB/418/Main/1/29/38; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Dixon to John Dixon.
    - Lease for possession of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 11 May 1798; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-43); GB/418/Main/1/29/39; Chetham's Library
      From Hugh Kidd to William Brittlebank.
    - Conveyance of estates in the counties of Cheshire and Staffordshire in trust to sell Hearwood House, 12 May 1798; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-44); GB/418/Main/1/29/40; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for possession of Hearwood House in Taxal co Ches, 28 Sep 1798; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-45); GB/418/Main/1/29/41; Chetham's Library
      From Cornelius Flint, William Brittlebank and Hugh Kidd to Matthew Pickford.
    - Assignment of a term of years in the Erwood estate in trust for Matthew Pickford, 29 Sep 1798; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-46); GB/418/Main/1/29/42; Chetham's Library
      From Charles Wheeldon (by direction of Hugh Kidd) to Matthew Pickford's trustee.
    - Lease for a year of Within Leaches in Taxal co Ches, 30 Jan 1799; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-47); GB/418/Main/1/29/43; Chetham's Library
      From Francis Jodrell to Matthew Pickford.
    - Conveyance of Two Within Leaches and Goyte's Head, Taxal co Ches, 31 Jan 1799; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-48); GB/418/Main/1/29/44; Chetham's Library
      From Francis Jodrell to Matthew Pickford and his trustee.
    - Deed of covenants for production of title deeds relating to estates in Taxal co Ches, 31 Jan 1799; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-49); GB/418/Main/1/29/45; Chetham's Library
      Conveyed by Francis Jodrell to Matthew Pickford.
    - Assignment of several estates in Fernileigh, county Derbys for the residue of a 1000 years term, 14 Oct 1802; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-50); GB/418/Main/1/29/46; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Needham and John Champion to Robert Needham.
    - Lease for a year of Barhead Farm, Fernileigh, co Derbys, 14 Oct 1802; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-51); GB/418/Main/1/29/47; Chetham's Library
      From William Needham to Hannah, Sarah and Martha Champion.
    - Mortgage in fee of estates in Fernileigh, co Derbys, 15 Oct 1802; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-52); GB/418/Main/1/29/48; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year of estates near Buxton, 19 May 1806; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-55); GB/418/Main/1/29/49; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Pickford and others to George Priestnall.
    - Release of estates in the counties of Chester, Lancaster and Derby in trust for Thomas and Matthew Pickford, 20 May 1806; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-56); GB/418/Main/1/29/50; Chetham's Library
      From the devisees in trust of Matthew Pickford and others to George Priestnall.
    - Lease for a year of Two Within Leaches and Goyt's Head, Taxal co Ches, 16 May 1808; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-58); GB/418/Main/1/29/51; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas and Matthew Pickford to Thomas Pickford and James Pickford etc.
    - Mortgage in fee of Two Within Leaches and Goyt's Head, Taxal co Ches, 17 May 1808; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-59); GB/418/Main/1/29/52; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas and Matthew Pickford to Thomas Pickford and others.
    - Lease for a year to vest possession of Two Within Leaches, Goyt's Head Farm, Goyt's Moss, Castidge estate etc, 6 Jan 1818; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-61); GB/418/Main/1/29/53; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Pickford, James Pickford, Thomas Parker, Bridget Worrall, Thomas Pickford and Matthew Pickford to Hon Edward Perceval.
    - Release by way of mortgage of divers farms in the counties of Chester and Derby for securing £18,678 3s 2d and interest, 7 Jan 1818; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-62); GB/418/Main/1/29/54; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Pickford and others to the Hon Edward Perceval.
    - Letters of administration of the effects of William Slack dec, 1 Oct 1818; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-63); GB/418/Main/1/29/55; Chetham's Library
      Extracted by George Lawton, Proctor, York.
    - Letters of administration of the effects of Henry Slack, dec, 1 Oct 1818; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-64); GB/418/Main/1/29/56; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of several terms of 500, 1000, 2000, 500 and 2000 years in freehold messuages and land situated in the parish of Taxal co Ches in trust for better securing £18678 3s 2d and interest, 3 Oct 1818; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-65); GB/418/Main/1/29/57; Chetham's Library
      Between Thomas Hewitt, Ralph Layster, John Dickinson and the executors of Edward Thornycroft by the direction of Thomas Pickford, and Matthew Pickford, and on the nomination of the Hon Edward Perceval to Sir William Earle Welby Bart.
    - Lease for a year of Two Within Leaches, Goyt's Head Farm etc, 11 Aug 1820; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-66); GB/418/Main/1/29/58; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas and Matthew Pickford to John Smith Daintry and John Ryle.
    - Mortgage in fee, 12 Aug 1820; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-67); GB/418/Main/1/29/59; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year of Two Within Leaches, Goyt's Moss, Castidge estate, Harwood House etc, Taxal co Ches, 8 Mar 1824; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-68); GB/418/Main/1/29/60; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas and Matthew Pickford and John Smith Daintry to John Ryle.
    - Conveyance of the equity of redemption in certain estates etc in the counties of Derby and Chester, 9 Mar 1824; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-69); GB/418/Main/1/29/61; Chetham's Library
    - Lease for a year and conveyance of Two Within Leaches and other lands in Taxal co Ches, 24 & 25 Mar 1830; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-72) & (2-73); GB/418/Main/1/29/62; Chetham's Library
      From John Ryle, Margaret Cecil, Mary and Isabella Perceval to Sir Charles Lemon, Edmund Henry Jodrell and Shakespear Phillips.
    - Lease for possession and mortgage in fee to Within Leaches, Erwood, Goyt's Head etc in Taxal co Ches, 24 & Jun 1830; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-75) & (2-76); GB/418/Main/1/29/63; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From the devisees in trust and heir at law of the late Francis Jodrell to James Norris and Richard Simpson.
    - Deed of covenants for the production of title deeds relating to estates in Taxal co Ches, 28 Aug 1832; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-77); GB/418/Main/1/29/64; Chetham's Library
      From John William Jodrell to Samuel Grimshaw.
    - Assignment of several terms of years affecting estates in Fernileigh co Derbys and Taxal co Ches in trust for Samuel Grimshaw and to attend the inheritance, 26 Nov 1834; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-78); GB/418/Main/1/29/65; Chetham's Library
      From William Crirle, Peter Browne and Joseph Firth to John Barlow and Stephen Heelis.
    - Assignment of a term of 500 years affecting premises in Taxal to the intent that the same may merge, 29 Aug 1832; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-79); GB/418/Main/1/29/66; Chetham's Library
      From Peter Browne to Samuel Grimshaw.
    - Lease for a year of lands etc in Fernileigh and Taxal, 25 Nov 1834; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-80); GB/418/Main/1/29/67; Chetham's Library
      From John William Jodrell and his mortgagees to Samuel Grimshaw.
    - Deed of covenants for the production of title deeds relating to estates in Fernileigh and Taxal, 26 Nov 1834; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-81); GB/418/Main/1/29/68; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance by feoffment of a plot of land in Hartington, co Derbys, 27 Aug 1836; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-82); GB/418/Main/1/29/69; Chetham's Library
      John Lomas to Samuel Grimshaw.
    - Lease and release of Barkers Farm, Fernileigh, co Derbys, 5 & 6 Jan 1838; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-83) & (2-84); GB/418/Main/1/29/70; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Needham to Sarah Champion.
    - Probate of the will and two codicils of James Clough, 30 Mar 1843; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-85); GB/418/Main/1/29/71; Chetham's Library
    - Acknowledgement of deed from Ellen Needham, 24 Oct 1843; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-86); GB/418/Main/1/29/72; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of Goyt's Moss in Taxal co Ches, 31 Dec 1890; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-87); GB/418/Main/1/29/73; Chetham's Library
      From Janet Grimshaw to Isaak Wattboulton.
      Term: 999 years.
      Rent: £5.
  - Documents relating to Warrington, co Ches, 1797-1808; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-41) & E.7.6 (2-57), (2-60); GB/418/Main/1/30; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Commission in militia forces given to John Leigh of Warrington, 10 Mar 1797; GB/418/E.7.5 (2-41); GB/418/Main/1/30/1; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of the will of John Leigh of Warrington, brewer, 1 Oct 1806; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-57); GB/418/Main/1/30/2; Chetham's Library
    - Probate of the will of Isaac Leigh of Warrington, 15 Dec 1808; GB/418/E.7.6 (2-60); GB/418/Main/1/30/3; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Wigan, co Lancs, 1752; GB/418/E.7.4 (195); GB/418/Main/1/31; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Bond for £240 and interest, 25 Mar 1752; GB/418/E.7.4 (195); GB/418/Main/1/31/1; Chetham's Library
      From Charles Houghton of Wigan to Thomas Houghton.
- The Chetham/Clowes Deeds, 15th century-19th century; GB/418/E.7.7-E.7.12 & E.8.3-E.8.14; GB/418/Main/2; 747 files; Chetham's Library
  The collection of over 700 documents was deposited in the Library by F. H. Mainprice of Taylor Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors to the Hospital and Library, in January 1942. The documents deal mainly with land in Salford, Broughton, Kersal and Manchester and date from the C15th-C19th. The order in which the Library received the documents has not been altered although deeds in some bundles have been placed in chronological order. The deeds are now found in 20 boxes. Descriptions of the collection were made by Hilda Lofthouse (Mun.E.7.7-E.7.12) and by Ian MacAlpine (E.8.3-14) (1990-91).